<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ITIL on Bossagyu Blog</title><link>https://bossagyu.com/en/tags/itil/</link><description>Recent content in ITIL on Bossagyu Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 08:53:36 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bossagyu.com/en/tags/itil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Explaining Capacity and Performance Management in ITIL v4</title><link>https://bossagyu.com/en/blog/020-itilv4-capacity-and-performance-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 08:53:36 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bossagyu.com/en/blog/020-itilv4-capacity-and-performance-management/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This article explains capacity and performance management as outlined in ITIL v4. I will also apply what I have understood to my own experiences, explaining the process of capacity and performance management.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-capacity-and-performance-management">What are Capacity and Performance Management?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Capacity and Performance Management involves managing the performance of services and the resources supporting them. The goal is to optimize the performance of services and ensure that the capacity of services is appropriately maintained.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="processes-in-capacity-and-performance-management">Processes in Capacity and Performance Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The processes in capacity and performance management include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Establishing Capacity and Performance Control&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analyzing and Improving Service Capacity and Performance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="establishing-capacity-and-performance-control">Establishing Capacity and Performance Control&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Establishing capacity and performance control involves agreeing with stakeholders on the usage and performance standards for the IT resources used by the service, and deciding on the timing, baseline, and format for evaluation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is realized through the following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Identifying service capacity and performance requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Agreeing on service capacity and performance requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deciding on capacity and performance requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designing capacity and performance evaluation metrics and reports&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Applying my experiences to these processes, I understood them as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Identifying service capacity and performance requirements
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>As an internal platform provider, I identified latency performance requirements (99%ile in Nms) demanded by internal users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Based on these thresholds, we conducted performance verification and measured throughput per instance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We calculated the cost based on the throughput measurements.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Agreeing on service capacity and performance requirements
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We agreed on latency performance and throughput with stakeholders.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deciding on capacity and performance requirements
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This remained unchanged from what was agreed upon.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designing capacity and performance evaluation metrics and reports
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We used a tracing tool called Dynatrace to measure and report performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="analyzing-and-improving-service-capacity-and-performance">Analyzing and Improving Service Capacity and Performance&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Analyze issues in usage and performance conditions from service output logs and incident information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is realized through the following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Analyzing capacity and performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reporting capacity and performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Planning and designing capacity and performance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Applying my experiences to these activities, I understood them as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Analyzing capacity and performance
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We used Dynatrace to analyze latency performance and throughput.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We identified performance issues from incident information.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reporting capacity and performance
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We visualized latency performance and throughput using Dynatrace&amp;rsquo;s dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Planning and designing capacity and performance
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Anticipating growth in users, we forecasted that the current capacity would be insufficient.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We made plans to increase capacity based on demand forecasts and executed them.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this article, I explained capacity and performance management based on what I have learned and applied it to my own experiences. I understood that capacity and performance management involves managing aspects similar to availability management, but from the perspective of capacity and performance.&lt;br>
In my experience, discussions about performance and availability often go hand in hand, and I rarely deal with them independently.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Explaining Business Analysis in ITIL v4</title><link>https://bossagyu.com/en/blog/018-itilv4-business-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 09:00:56 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bossagyu.com/en/blog/018-itilv4-business-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This article consolidates my learning and understanding of business analysis as per ITIL v4. I will also apply my own experiences to explain the business analysis process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-business-analysis">What is Business Analysis?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Business analysis involves analyzing a business or any other component to propose solutions for meeting those needs or solving business challenges. It is important to note that the term &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; analysis does not solely pertain to business entities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="examples-of-business-analysis-techniques">Examples of Business Analysis Techniques&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Examples of business analysis techniques include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>SWOT Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User Stories&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For specific methods, I defer to other sites as they are not the main focus here. Personally, I often use Customer Journey Maps, although it is not listed as an example here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-business-analysis-process">The Business Analysis Process&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The business analysis process includes two main processes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Designing and Maintaining Business Analysis Approaches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying Business Analysis and Solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="designing-and-maintaining-business-analysis-approaches">Designing and Maintaining Business Analysis Approaches&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This process focuses on establishing a consistent and effective approach to business analysis by addressing the current and anticipated needs of the organization. It is executed as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Analyzing the organization and requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reviewing business analysis approach methodologies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implementing the business analysis approach&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In my organization, we rarely conduct analysis at the business layer level. Generally, this process involves analyzing specific requirements using certain methodologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="identifying-business-analysis-and-solutions">Identifying Business Analysis and Solutions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This process emphasizes analyzing stakeholders&amp;rsquo; needs and requirements. It includes identifying and proposing solutions to address the stakeholders&amp;rsquo; needs and requirements. It is executed as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Collecting and analyzing information from stakeholders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Defining solution options and identifying recommended solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Providing support to the solution delivery team&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evaluating and assessing the performance of the solution&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Applying my own experiences to these activities, I understood them as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="for-12">For 1,2&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Collecting information from stakeholders and conducting analysis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying the issues to be solved (why) from the analysis results and determining what solutions are available (what).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="for-3">For 3&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Considering how to solve the identified why and what with the product team.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deciding on the resolution method and evaluation criteria to determine how success will be measured.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="for-4">For 4&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Regularly evaluating how well the solution meets the established criteria.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I recommend automating data collection and visualizing it with tools like Grafana for visibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This article explained business analysis based on my learning and experiences. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve understood that business analysis does not only target businesses and includes processes beyond analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference">Reference&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.axelos.com/resource-hub/practice/business-analysis-management-itil-4-practice-guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Business analysis management: ITIL 4 Practice Guide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>